&gt;&gt; Good morning.
&gt;&gt; 早上好
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
Welcome to Focus Interaction in
欢迎来到 tvOS 11 的
tvOS 11.
焦点交互发布会
My name is Matt, I'm a software
我的名字是 Matt  我是负责
engineer working on UIKit and
UIKit 的软件工程师
I'll be joined later today by my
今天另一位将要上台讲话的是
colleague Jon.
我的同事 Jon
We have a lot to cover today, so
我们有很多东西想要讨论  那么
let's get started.
我们赶快开始吧
First, we're going to showcase
首先 我们将要向大家示范
some of the new features and
我们在 tvOS 11 里
enhancements that we've made for
为焦点交互支持
Focus Interaction support in
而设计的一些新功能
tvOS 11.
和各项改进
These cover a number of requests
它们涵盖了过去一年
that we've received from you
我们从大家这里收集到的
over the past year.
众多需求信息
Next, Focus Interaction support
第二  焦点交互支持
is now in SceneKit and so we're
现在已经纳入 SceneKit
going to cover everything that
所以我们准备讲一讲
you need to know in order to get
大家在上手前需要了解的
started.
所有信息
And finally, we've built some
最后 我们在 tvOS 11 里开发了一些
great new focus debugging tools
很棒的焦点调试新工具
in tvOS 11 for helping you
用来帮助大家
diagnose focus related issues in
在自己的 App 里诊断与焦点相关的
your app.
问题
We think these new tools are
我们认为这些新工具
going to save you a ton of time.
将会给你们节省大量时间
But before we start it's
不过在开始之前
important that we review some of
我们有必要回顾一些基础内容
the basics of how the Focus API
看看 Focus API 是如何
works into tvOS 11.
在 tvOS 11 里运作的
This information is going to be
这个信息很重要
important throughout our session
它将贯穿于今天这个会议的
today.
全程
From the perspective of the
从聚焦引擎的角度来看
focus engine your app is app is
大家的 App 是由
made up of focus items and focus
聚焦项和聚焦环境
environments.
构成的
Focus items are the user
聚焦项属于
interface elements that are
用户界面元素
capable of becoming focused.
它可以形成聚焦
They conform to the UIFocusItem
它们遵循的是 UIFocusItem
item protocol.
的项目协议
Examples of focus items include
聚焦项的例子包括
UIViews in UIKit and nodes in
UIKit 里的 UIView  还有 SpriteKit 里的
SpriteKit.
节点
Focus environments conform to
聚焦环境遵循的是
the UIFocusEnvironment protocol.
UIFocusEnvironment 协议
Environments are allowed to
聚焦环境可以用来影响
influence the focus behavior in
你应用程序里的聚焦行为
your application and they also
而且它们还会收到关于
get notified about focus
焦点更新的
updates.
通知
All focus items are also focus
所有的聚焦项同时也是聚焦环境
environments, but these also
但聚焦环境还包括
cover other objects like view
其他对象 例如视图
controllers.
控制器
Focus items and focus
聚焦项和聚焦环境
environments are arranged in a
都按照等级次序进行
hierarchy.
排列
In UIKit this hierarchy loosely
在 UIKit 里面 这个等级次序
follows the view and view
只是大致对应视图与
controller hierarchies and in
视图控制器的等级
SpriteKit it follows the node
和在 SpriteKit 里面 它对应着节点的
hierarchy.
等级次序
This hierarchy is important when
这个等级次序在涉及到
it comes to getting notified
接收焦点更新通知时
about focus updates.
就显得很重要
A focus update can happen in one
焦点更新的形成方式可以是
of two ways.
两种方法里的一种
First, a user can move focus
首先 用户能够以几何模式
geometrically, such as by
移动焦点
swiping on the Siri remote or
例如在 Siri 遥控器
your app can trigger a
或你的 App 上轻扫一下
programmatic focus update, such
就会触发一个程序性焦点更新
as by calling APIs like
就像是调用某些 setNeedsFocusUpdate
setNeedsFocusUpdate.
这样的 API
When a focus update happens, we
焦点更新产生时
notify every focus environment
我们会通知所有聚焦环境
that contains both the
这些环境既包含
previously focused item and the
先前的已聚焦项  以及
next focused item.
即将聚焦的项
And this includes all common
这同样也包括所有的
ancestor environments as well.
共同原始环境
We notify environments in
我们用升序方法
ascending order starting with
来通知环境
the two items that are directly
从直接参与更新的两个项
involved in the update.
开始
Notifications are sent by
通知传送的形式
calling the didUpdateFocus
是通过调用 didUpdateFocus 功能
method, which is defined on the
这个功能定义是在
UIFocusEnvironment protocol.
UIFocusEnvironment 协议之上的
And this leads us straight into
这就直接引出了
our first topic of today, which
我们今天的第一个话题
is that in tvOS 11 we're
就是 在 tvOS 11 里
providing a few helpful new ways
我们要提供一些很有帮助的新办法
to get notified about focus
以便更好地接收
updates.
焦点更新通知
Let's jump back to that diagram.
我们回到刚才的图表
Like I was just saying, we
就像我刚才说的  我们
notify your app using this
通知你的 App 使用这个
didUpdateFocus method defined on
根据 UIFocusEnvironment 定义的
UIFocusEnvironment.
didUpdateFocus 功能
But sometimes there might be
但有时你的 App 里可能会有
another object in your app not a
另外的对象  它并不是
focus environment that you don't
聚焦环境  而你并不想
want to be loosely coupled to
让它和你其余的
the rest of your user interface
用户界面代码
code.
结合起来
So, for this case we're
因此  针对这种情况
introducing a new foundation
我们要介绍一个新的基础
notification type called
通知类型
UIFocusDidUpdate.
叫做 UIFocusDidUpdate
And you can observe this from
你从 App 中的任何地方都可以
anywhere in your app and it will
看到它  每一次
get sent every time focus
焦点更新都会发送这个
updates.
通知
This notification includes all
这个通知里面的信息
the same information that you're
跟你习惯的通过
used to getting for a normal
常规焦点更新而接收的
focus update, including a
信息相同
context that describes the
包括一个更新的情况
update, as well as an animation
还有一个动画协调器
coordinator for controlling
以便用来控制
visual feedback.
视觉反馈
You can access both of these
这两个对象你都可以访问
objects using two new user info
只要你使用我们准备提供的
keys that we're providing.
两款新的用户信息密钥就可以
The UIFocusUpdateContext key and
UIFocusUpdateContext 密钥  还有
the UIFocusUpdate
UIFocusUpdate
AnimiationCoordinator key.
AnimiationCoordinator 密钥
We're also introducing another
我们还要介绍另一个
key notification type related to
有关焦点更新的
focus updates and that's called
密钥通知类型
UIFocusMovementDidFail and this
叫做 UIFocusMovementDidFail
notification is sent whenever
只要用户尝试
the user tries, but fails to
但却无法把焦点移到某个方向
move focus in a certain
通知就会被
direction.
发送出去
This will only be sent when the
而这个通知  只有在用户试图移动焦点
user is trying to move focus not
而你的 App 却无法执行
when your app fails to perform
某种程序性的焦点更新时
some kind of programmatic focus
通知才会被发送
update.
出去
And this is really useful for
这个确实很有用
cases where you might want to
当用户试图向某个方向
provide some kind of feedback to
移动焦距  但又不被允许这样做
the user when they try to move
而你想给用户提供某种反馈
focus in a direction that
这个功能就可以
they're not allowed to.
派上用场
Now a good example of this is on
有一个很好的例子
Apple TV where VoiceOver will
就是在 Apple TV 上  当用户
provide a sound when a user
试图向未获许可的方向
tries to move focus in a
移动焦距时
direction that they're not
VoiceOver 将会提供一个
allowed to.
警示声音
And this is a really helpful way
这确实是一种有效的方式
to provide some extra auditory
它给视力受损的用户
feedback to visually impaired
提供了某种额外的听觉反馈
users letting them know that
让他们能够知道
their action was appropriately
自己的操作指令已被明确无误地
received, but that it didn't
接收到  但是却
have any effect.
无法生效
So that's it for focus update
这就是我们关于焦点更新
notifications.
通知的内容
We're also providing a few new
我们还在
helpful protocol extensions on
UIFocusEnvironment 和
the UIFocusEnvironment and
UIFocusItem 协议基础上
UIFocusItem protocols to help
提供了一些有用的协议扩展
you write more succinct and
是用来帮你编写更加简洁
safer code.
更安全的代码
The first of these is a pretty
首先要介绍的这个
easy one we're adding an
协议扩展很简单
isFocused property to the
我们把 isFoucused 属性
UIFocusItem protocol and this is
添加到 UIFocusItem 协议
just a simple way to check if
这是一种很简便的方式 可以查看
any item is currently focused.
当前有没有项目处在聚焦状态
We've exposed this property on
自从 tvOS 9 以来 我们就把
UIView since tvOS 9, but now
这个属性展示在 UIView 上
that we're exposing it on the
现在我们要将它直接展示在
protocol UIFocusItem item
协议 UIFocusItem 项目上
directly you can use this with
你可以把它和任何类型的
any type of focus item and that
聚焦项在一起使用
includes SpriteKit nodes.
包括 SpriteKit 节点
We've also added a new contains
我们还把一种新的 contains 功能添加到了
method to the UIFocusEnvironment
UIFocusEnvironment
protocol.
协议里
This method allows you to easily
你可以使用这个方法
check if one focus environment
轻松查看有没有哪个聚焦环境里
contains another focus
包含了另一个聚焦环境
environment, but without having
而无需了解那些
to know the underlying types
在查看过程中涉及的
involved in the check.
隐含类型
Let's look at an example of
我们来看看下面这个
this.
例子
Suppose we want to check if an
假设我们想要查看一下
item that just got focused is
有没有哪个刚完成的聚焦项
contained by our current view
包含在当前的视图
controller.
控制器里
We can accomplish this by simply
要完成这项操作
calling the contains method on
我们只需要调用视图控制器上的
the view controller itself and
contains 功能  然后再
passing in the next focus item
直接转入下一个
directly.
聚焦项
This will work if that item is a
如果这个项是一个视图
view, it'll work if it's a
那么这种做法就会奏效  如果是
SpriteKit node, it doesn't
一个 SpriteKit 节点 也可以
matter what the types are
不管涉及到哪些类型
involved, you can just call
你只需要
contains and it'll just work.
调用 contains  它就能发挥作用
And so, this will hopefully cut
因此 它将有望
down on the amount of
降低你需要
typecasting that you have to
在代码里执行的
perform in your code.
类型转换量
So that's it for new protocol
这就是新协议扩展的
extensions.
情况
For our next enhancements, I'd
关于其他的性能提升
like to invite up my colleague
我要请我的同事 Jon
Jon to talk to you about some
上台与大家分享一些
new APIs for focus animations.
聚焦动画的新 API
&gt;&gt; Good morning, last year we
&gt;&gt; 早上好 去年我们
showed you the coordination API
为大家展示过协调 API
that you can use to keep your
它可以让你的动画
animations in sync with the
在焦点更新的过程中
system animations during a focus
与系统动画
update.
保持同步
And this is done by using the
完成这一点  靠的就是
UIFocusAnimationCoordinator that
UIFocusAnimationCoordinator
is provided whenever a focus
无论焦点更新在何时发生
update occurs.
它都会立刻启动
Today, I'd like to talk to you
今天 我想跟大家聊聊
about some enhancements that
我们在 tvOS 11 里
we've made to this API in tvOS
为这个 API 做出的一些
11.
改进
But before I get started let's
但在开始之前
take a more in-depth look at how
让我们更深入地看一下
animations work today.
今天的动画是怎样运作的
Focus animations are a really
聚焦动画是
important part of the tvOS user
tvOS 用户体验中非常重要的
experience.
一部分
Not only do they show your users
它们不仅会给你的用户展示
where focus has moved they help
焦点移动的方位
them feel more connected with
还让用户感到与你的内容
your content.
联系得更加密切
But as with most things, timing
跟大多数事情一样  时序把握
is essential.
是关键
If the animations are too fast
如果动画速度过快
it creates a jarring effect for
就会给用户带来
your users.
不愉快的感觉
And if they're too slow well
但如果动画速度过慢
they're getting in the way.
就会影响使用
So, UIKit has a lot of work put
所以  UIKit 在这方面花费了很大一番
into it to manage these
气力  目的就是要管理这些
animations and their timing.
动画及其时序
We do a lot of manipulations,
我们进行了大量操控
such as duration changes, to
比如改变时长
keep the animations feeling
来使动画效果
fluid.
更流畅
Quicker movements through
在多个聚焦项之间
multiple focus items will result
加快移动速度  会形成
in quicker animations.
更为快速的动画效果
And when we move slowly from one
当我们从一个项缓慢移动到
item to the next we slow down
下一项时  就会相应地放慢动画
the animations to match.
来匹配这个速度
When a user moves focus to an
当用户把焦点
item offscreen we make sure to
移动到画面外时
add an appropriate delay until
我们要确保能够增添适度的延迟
that item is fully visible
直至该项完全可见
before we perform the focusing
然后我们再运行聚焦
animations.
动画
And you might have noticed that
大家可能已经注意到了
focusing animations and
聚焦动画和
unfocusing animations have a
失焦动画各自有一套
different set of timing.
不同的时序
This is because focusing
这是因为聚焦
animations should be prominent
动画需要清晰分明
and they should grab the user's
要抓住用户的眼球
attention, whereas unfocusing
而失焦动画
animations should be subtler and
则需要更加隐约一些
more in the background.
更多的是作为背景
So, you can see here as focus
所以  大家在这里可以看到
moves between these items, the
当焦点在这些项目之间移动时
item becoming focused pops up
被聚焦的项就会
very quickly and the item
迅速凸显
becoming unfocused slowly moves
而失焦的项就会缓慢地移动到
into the background.
背景位置
In fact, it leaves a trail
事实上 当焦点从这里
behind it as focus has moved
移动到下一项时
from it to the next item.
会在后方留下一道痕迹
So, when you call
于是 当你调用
addCoordinatedAnimations to
addCoordinatedAnimations
synchronize your animations we
来同步你的动画时
automatically determine whether
我们会根据聚焦环境的
these are focusing or unfocusing
等级次序来自动判断
animations based on the focus
这些是聚焦动画
environment hierarchy.
还是失焦动画
So, here's the same diagram Matt
这是 Matt 刚才
showed earlier for the
展示的同一张图表
didUpdateFocus notifications.
是关于 didUpdateFocus 通知的
Whenever you call
不论你何时要调用
addCoordinatedAnimations from
addCoordinatedAnimations
either the previously focused
不论是从先前被聚焦的项
item or any of its direct
还是从它的任何直系原始项调用
ancestors up to but not
只是不包括
including the common parent
共同的母环境
environment we consider these
我们都会认为这些
unfocusing animations and we
是失焦动画
coordinate them as such.
并以此对它们进行调节
Conversely, if your animations
相反 如果你的动画添加来源
are added from either the next
是下一个聚焦项
focused item or any of its
或者它的任何
direct ancestors we consider
直系原始项  那么
these focusing animations and so
我们就认为这些是聚焦动画
they get that more prominent
然后它们就会被
timing.
优先处理
And this works really well.
效果真的很好
But in tvOS 11 we're now
但是在 tvOS 11里  我们现在
allowing you to specifically
允许大家将具体目标或是设定为
target either the focusing or
聚焦动画  或是设定为
unfocusing animations.
失焦动画
And we're doing this by adding
为了这个目的  我们把两个
two new methods to the UIFocus
新功能添加到了
AnimationCoordinator,
UIFocusAnimationCoordinator
addCoordinated
addCoordinated
FocusingAnimations and
FocusingAnimations
UnfocusingAnimations.
UnfocusingAnimations
So, addCoordinated
这样一来  addCoordinated
FocusingAnimations will function
FocusingAnimations 的运作模式
exactly the same as if you call
几乎就像是你从
addCoordinatedAnimations from
即将聚焦的项内部
within the next focused item or
或是从它任何一个直系原始项里
any of its direct ancestors.
调用 addCoordinatedAnimations 一样
And addCoordinated
而 addCoordinated
UnfocusingAnimations will
UnfocusingAnimations 的
function the same as
运作模式跟 addCoordinatedAnimations 从
addCoordinatedAnimations from
前一个聚焦项内部
within the previous focused item
或是它的原始项里
or its ancestors.
调用一样
And so, the best way to show you
那么  给大家展示这个运作方式的
how this works is with a demo.
最好办法就是演示一遍
So, let's dive right in.
好  我们直接开始吧
All right, so I'm working a very
好了 我要做一个非常
simple timeline application that
简单的时间轴应用
shows some entries from past
它会显示以前 WWDC
dubdub events and their
的一些事件以及这些事件的
keynotes.
演示文稿
And each entry is represented by
每个条目都由这个
this cell that has a number in
包含数字的单元代表
it and as we move focus the
当我们移动焦点时
corresponding image above moves
它上方对应的图片会向下移动
down to give a little bit of
这是为了稍微突出
emphasis.
强调一下
As I move through these you
当我在这样移动的过程中
might notice that it feels a
你可能会注意到
little bit choppy as we move
如果我们加快移动速度  会有些
quickly.
不太流畅
Well let's hop over and take a
那我们就跳过这个问题
look at the code.
来看一下代码
And you'll see that everything
大家可以看到
is done within the
所有操作都已经在
addCoordinatedAnimations block.
addCoordinatedAnimations 部分中完成
And this is a great use for our
这是我们的新 API 的一个很好的用途
new API, what we have here is
我们在这里展示的是
the focusing view and I've
焦点视图
gotten a reference to this by
我已经通过 nextFocusedIndexPath
using the nextFocusedIndexPath
把它关联起来
to grab the supplementary view
这样就可以抓取它
it corresponds with and I'm
对应的补充视图  我只需要
simply doing a transform of 100
做出向下 100 点的
points down.
坐标转换就可以了
And then similarly for the
失焦视图的情况
unfocusing view the image that's
也与此相似
going back up I get it by using
这个退到后面的图片  我使用
the previouslyFocusedIndexPath
previouslyFocusedIndexPath 来抓取它
and then transforming to the
然后根据其特征属性
identity.
进行转换
So instead of using the single
因此  我们没有使用单一的
addCoordinatedAnimations call
addCoordinatedAnimations 功能
which in fact makes everything
事实上这就让所有事情都
coordinate alongside the
根据聚焦动画
focusing animations, we can now
来进行协调  我们现在可以
split this up into two explicit
把它分为两个显性的调用
calls, one for the focusing
一个是为了
animations for the focusing view
获得焦点视图的聚焦动画
and then one for the unfocusing
另一个是为了获得
animations for the unfocusing
失焦视图的失焦
view.
动画
So, now let's rerun this and
现在我们再运行一次
take a look.
看看情况怎样
Now as we move from one item to
现在我们将焦点从一个项
the next you can see that the
移动到下一项 这时你就可以发现
same trail as focus moves in the
与焦点自身在单元里移动时
cells itself exists in the image
相同的移动轨迹存在于
views themselves and this
图像视图自身  这就
creates a much nicer user
为你应用程序
experience for your application.
的用户体验增色不少
All right, so now let's hope
好了 现在我们再跳回到
back over to the slides.
幻灯片
And there's one other thing I'd
在动画方面
like to talk about regarding
我还有一件事情
animations.
跟大家谈谈
In addition to the two new
除了上述两个新功能以外
methods we're also providing an
我们还提供了一个
instance of the
关于 UIFocusAnimationContext
UIFocusAnimationContext and this
例证  这是
is a new object in tvOS 11 that
tvOS 11 里的一个新对象
gives you some additional timing
它会给你额外提供一些
information about the animations
关于动画发生时序的信息
occurring which should make
它应该会让
advance animations even easier.
动画的推进变得更为轻松
So, let's say we'd like to run
比如说 在这个系统聚焦
an animation during the second
动画的后半部分
half of the system focusing
我们想要运行
animations.
动画
Well this is very easy to do,
这个嘛很容易实现
all we need to do is grab the
我们只需要从
duration off of the animation
动画情景里抓取出时长
context, divide it by two, and
把它分为两部分
then pass these values into the
再把这些数值传送到
standard UIView animate method
普通的 UIView 动画功能中
and we're done.
事情就完成了
One important point to mention
我想重点提一下
is the overrideInheritedDuration
是你必须打开 overrideInheritedDuration 选项
option that needs to get passed
因为
in because without this the
如果做不到这一点
nested view based animations are
基于嵌套视图的动画就会忽略
going to ignore the duration
你给定的时长
that you gave and instead use
并且转而选用
the outer duration.
外部时长
But this doesn't just make you
但如果这样做了  就不仅会让你的
UIVIewAnimation easier it also
UIVIewAnimation 变得更简单
provides better non-UIKit
它还提供更好的 non-UIKit
support.
支持
So, if you're using SpriteKit
所以  如果你使用充分获得了
which is fully supported by the
聚焦系统支持的 SpriteKit
focus system it allows you to
你就可以为自己的动画
create a more consistent feel
创造更为一致的感觉
for your animations using SK
举例来说  你可以使用
actions for example.
SK 操作
This is an example of using SK
这是一个使用 SK 操作的例证
actions to fade the opacity to
它把不透明度减弱到 50%
50% using the exact same timing
使用的是与系统 UIKit
that the system UIKit focusing
聚焦动画完全相同
animations would.
的时序
All right, so the existing API
好了 所以说现在的 API
works really well.
运行效果确实很好
And if you don't have a need to
如果你不需要
explicitly target either
明确定位
focusing or unfocusing continue
聚焦或失焦
using the existing API because
你可以继续使用现在的 API
it does the right thing for you.
因为它正好符合你的需求
However, if you need to target
不过 如果你需要把你的
your animations to focusing or
动画定位为
unfocusing regardless of their
聚焦或失焦
association with the focus
而不管它们与
environment hierarchy use the
聚焦环境等级的联系
new APIs and you'll be able to
那就使用新的 API
do that to great effect.
这样你能获得极好的效果
And lastly, the focus animation
最后 我们还为某种
context is provided for some
附加时序信息提供了
additional timing information
聚焦动画情景
which should make advanced
这会使得高级动画操作
animations even easier.
变得更容易
So, next I'd like to talk about
那么 接下来我想谈谈
focus sounds.
聚焦音效
Where animations give a visual
动画是焦点更新的
representation of the focus
视觉表现
update focus sounds provide an
聚焦音效则为用户
auditory queue to the user that
提供焦点移动后形成的
focus has moved.
听觉队列
And just like animations there's
和动画的情况一样
some subtlety to sound playback
声音回放具有某种微妙特征
to create the best user
可以形成效果最佳的
experience possible.
用户体验
UIKit performs a number of
UKit 针对播放的每个音效
volume and panning modifications
会执行好几种
to every sound that's played.
音量和连贯性的修正
So, faster focus movements
焦点移动的速度越快
result in a quieter sound and
它造成的音效越安静
slower focus movements result in
焦点移动速度越慢
a louder sound, which nicely
音效就越大
complements the same duration
这就极好地补足了
modifications we make to
我们针对动画而做出的
animations.
同一时长调整
We also use the location of the
我们还可以运用屏幕上
focusing item onscreen to pan
聚焦项所处的位置
the volume either stereo left or
把声音选定为左声道
stereo right.
或右声道
So, if you swipe right across
如果在屏幕上向右轻扫
the screen you'll notice sound
你会注意到声音开始
starts to pan to the right and
转到右声道
as you swipe back left you'll
如果你反过来向左轻扫
notice sound pans to the left
而焦点位于水平正中央时
bouncing out when focus is
声音转向左声道的
centered horizontally.
提示就会弹出
Again, this helps create a much
这再次有助于创建一种
more immersive user experience.
更加浸润式的用户体验
But a lot of requested that we
很多用户希望我们能够
allow you to provide custom
让大家提供自定义聚焦音效
focus sounds or to opt out of
或者从 UIKit 音效里退出  现在在 tvOS 11 里
the UIKit sounds and started in
我很高兴地宣布
tvOS 11 I'm happy to announce
这两件事情
that we're allowing you to do
大家现在都可以
both.
去做了
So, to play custom sounds you
那么  现在如果播放自定义音效
simply need to register your
你只需要使用一个标识符
sound with an identifier and
注册你的音效
then provide that identifier
然后在焦点更新时
during a focus update that will
提供这个标识符  这样就可以
play a focus sound.
播放聚焦音效了
This is only a user initiated
这只是用户启动的一种
focus movement.
焦点移动
And then once we have that
我们收到这个标识符以后
identifier we'll play the sound
就会播放与之关联的
it's associated with.
的音效
To register sounds you'll use a
注册音效需要使用一个类
class method register
即 registersoundFileURL
soundFileURL for sound
用于音效
identifier which is exposed on
标识符 它显现在
the new UIFocusSystem, a new
新的 UIFocusSystem 上
object in tvOS 11.
是 tvOS 11 中的一个新对象
The sound registration is a
音效注册的操作是全局性的
global action, meaning that once
也就是说 一旦完成注册
you do it that custom sound is
你的自定义音效
available throughout your entire
在整个应用程序里都可以
application.
使用
Because of this, you should only
由于这个原因 一个音效
register a sound for a single
只应该注册一个
identifier.
标识符
In fact, reregistering with the
事实上 使用同一个音效标识符
same sound identifier is an
反复注册是
error.
错误操作
But it's perfectly acceptable
但是 如果你的 App 里有多个
and reasonable to have multiple
音效  则是完全合理
sounds in your application, just
可以接受
give each one of them a unique
只需要让每个音效对应某个特别的
identifier.
标识符就可以
Because it's global you also
由于这个操作是全局性的
want to register early.
你最好是提前注册
There's a nontrivial performance
如果要设置并播放你的自定义音效
cost to setting up your custom
会产生不小的
sounds for playback and we want
性能成本  所以我们想确保
to make sure there's as much
在注册和用户的焦点移动之间
time between registration and
有充裕的时间
user focus movement so that
来保证音效
sounds can play seamlessly.
得以无缝播放
The registration method accepts
这个注册方法支持所有
all standard iOS file formats
储存在你本地设备的
that are locally stored on your
标准 iOS 文件
device.
格式
So, when you actually need to
所以 当你真正需要
play the sound you'll use the
播放这一音效时
new optional method on the
你会使用到 UIFocusEnvironment
UIFocusEnvironment protocol.
一个新的可选功能
So, we call this method
因此  我们把这一方法
soundIdentifier
称为 soundIdentifier
ForFocusUpdate.
ForFocusUpdate
In the same ascending order that
那么 didUpdateFocus 的通知
the didUpdateFocus notifications
也是以同样的升序方式
are delivered.
进行传送
And we start by calling this
我们开始是在下一个聚焦项上
method on the next focused item.
调用这个方法
If the next focused item gives
如果下一个聚焦项给我们
us a no focus sound identifier
提供了一个失焦音效标识符
we use that to control sound
我们就用它来给这个焦点更新
playback for this focus update
控制音效回放
and then we're done.
这样就可以了
However, if we don't get a sound
不过 如果我们从下一个
identifier back from the next
聚焦项目里没有获得返回的
focus item we look to its parent
音效标识符  我们就要查看它的父项
and we try again.
然后再试一次
Now if the parent doesn't return
现在如果这个父项没有返回任何信息
anything we repeat this process
我们就一遍遍地重复这个过程
and we go up to its parent and
我们向上查看它的父项
we repeat this over and over
然后多次重复这个过程
until we get to the root focus
直到我们抵达根聚焦环境
environment which if none of
如果你所有的聚焦环境
your focus environments have
都没有选择提供一个自定义音效
chosen to provide a custom sound
我们就会直接选用
then we simply use the default
UIKit 自身使用的
that UIKit would use on its own.
默认音效
So, there are a number of
所以 你从焦点更新时使用的
options for what values you
音效标识符那里
might return from sound
可能获得的返回值
identifier for focus update.
具有多种选择可能性
Of course, you're able to return
你当然可以
any of the sounds that you had
返回自己先前曾经注册过的
previously registered and doing
任何音效  这样一来
so will play the sound that that
注册该标识符的音效
identifier was registered with.
就会被播放出来
UIKit also provides two sound
UIKit 还提供两种音效标识符
identifiers, default and none.
默认标识和无标识
By providing the default sound
通过提供默认音效标识符
identifier it explicitly signals
UIKit 可以得到明确的信号
to UIKit that you want to force
也就是说 你想强制
the default sound that UIKit
UIKit 自带的默认音效
would play on its own to be
将会为这一次的焦点更新
played for this focus update.
而自行播放
Now keep in mind if none of your
现在请记住  如果你所有的
environments wish to control
环境都不希望控制这个更新的
sound for this update then this
音效
is value we'll use anyway.
那么  这就是我们要使用的值
So, it's probably rare you'll
你需要使用它的机会可能很少
need to use, this provide this
但我们仍提供这个
for the cases that you do.
以备不时之需
And last, the non-identifier can
最后 非标识符可以
be used to entirely opt out of
用来彻底退出播放
focus sounds for this focus
此次焦点更新的
update.
聚焦音效
You're able to very easily
你可以非常轻松地
conditionally modify which sound
有条件修改调整
is played and using the same
要播放的音效  并且使用
contains protocol extension that
Matt 之前展示过的
Matt showed earlier we're able
同样的 contains 协议扩展
to determine when focus moves
我们能够决定
through a particular environment
焦点在某个具体环境里移动的时间
and when it does modify the
以及它修改调整音效的时间
sound, otherwise deferred to
不然就延迟它的
pair it.
匹配进度
So, I here I have a particular
看  我现在设定了一个
environment, I'll call it sound
具体的环境  我称它为
enabled environment where when
音效启动环境
focus moves through this
当焦点在这个环境里
environment I want to play a
移动时  我想播放先前
sound that I registered with my
我用自定义音效标识符注册过的
custom sound identifier.
一个音效
Again, it's very easy to do,
这同样也很简单
take the next focused item and
选取下一个聚焦项
then just check whether or not
然后只要再检查一下
that's contained within the
它是否包含在这个
sound enabled environment.
音效启动环境里
So, a couple quick points on
那么  关于从聚焦音效里退出的问题
opting out of focus sounds.
我简单再讲几点
First, users expect a sound to
第一 用户期待在焦点移动发生时
be played when focus movement
能够出现音效
occurs.
播放
Like I mentioned before, this is
就像我前面提到的  焦点移动
an auditory queue to them that
对于它们来说就是一个
focus has moved.
声音队列
So, you should only be opting
所以你应该仅仅在
out of sounds if the user is
用户明确表示不要播放音效的时候
explicitly expected to.
退出音效
A great example of this might be
举一个很好的例子
an in-game menu where the user
比如在游戏内菜单中
can turn off sounds for your
用户可以关闭
entire application.
整个 App 里的音效
Also, if you were think about
如果你想要
opting out of focus sounds and
退出聚焦音效
then playing your own when a
然后在焦点更新产生后
focus update occurs, I highly
播放自己的音效
encourage you to use our API
我强烈推荐大家改用我们的 API
instead because not only do you
因为你不仅仅可以
get the same volume and panning
由此而获得音量和连贯性的各项调整
adjustments that we perform for
这些调整是我们为自己的
our internal sounds which are
内部音效而实施的
probably very hard to replicate.
它可能很难被复制
We also respect the user's
同时 我们也尊重用户
device settings for playing
为了播放这些音效
these sounds.
而对设备进行的设置
So, Apple TV has a setting that
因此 Apple TV 的一个设置
allows you to turn off
就是允许你关闭
navigation sounds for the entire
整个系统的导航音效
system and you don't want your
如果用户已经说他们不愿意要这些音效了
application to be the only one
你肯定不想让你的 App
playing sounds if the user says
成为唯一一个
they don't want them.
播放音效的 App
All right, so to recap.
好的 再概括一下
You should use good judgment
你应该通过良好判断
when determining when and where
来决定什么时候 在什么地方
and which sounds to play for
以及为焦点更新播放什么音效
focus update because your sound
因为你的音效
should enhance the user
应该用来改善用户体验
experience they should not
用体验抓住
detract from it.
他们的注意力而不是分散注意力
A great example of this might be
这方面有一个很好的例子
differentiating between elements
应该就是屏幕显示元素的
onscreen.
差异化
We do this in UIKit based on the
我们在 UIKit 上就是根据
size of particular items.
具体项的大小而这样做的
So, very large focus items have
因此 超大的聚焦项会产生
a larger, deeper sound and
更响亮  更低沉的音效
smaller items have a smaller,
而较小的聚焦项
higher pitched sound.
音效就比较轻 音调更高
Again, this is all to enhance
同样 这样做都是为了改善
the user experience.
用户体验
All right and with that I'd like
好的 说了这么多 现在我要把
to turn things back over to Matt
讲台交还给 Matt 了
who will talk about support for
他会谈一谈 SceneKit 支持的
SceneKit.
相关事宜
Matt.
Matt
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; Thanks Jon.
谢谢 Jon
All right, I'm excited to
好的 我很兴奋地
announce that in tvOS 11 we're
向大家宣布 在 tvOS 11 里
now extending focus system
我们要把焦点系统支持
support into the SceneKit
扩展到 SceneKit 的
framework.
框架上
So, how does this work?
那么  它如何工作呢
Well if you recall back to tvOS
大家不妨回想一下 tvOS 9
9 it used to be that UIView was
在以前  UIView 是
the only type that was able to
唯一能够支持聚焦的
be focused.
类型
In tvOS 10 we introduced this
而在 tvOS 10 里  我们采用了
new UI focused item protocol and
这种新的 UI 聚焦项协议
we extended focus interaction
此外  我们把焦点交互支持
support into SpriteKit by
扩展到了 SpriteKit
adopting this protocol on both
办法是将这个协议同时
UIView and SKNode.
纳入 UIView 和 SKNode
Well now in tvOS 11 we're adding
那么在现在的 tvOS 11 里 我们要
SCNNode to the UIFocusItem
把 SCNNode 加入 UIFocusItem
family.
族项
So, how does this work?
那么  这是如何进行的呢？
Just like SpriteKit you need to
就像 SpriteKit 一样
opt in in order to get focus
你需要先加入  然后在你的
support in your SceneKit apps.
SceneKit App 里获得焦点支持
This means that nodes are not
这就意味着在默认状态下
focusable by default.
节点是无法聚焦的
In order to make them focusable
要让这些节点可以聚焦
it couldn't be easier, all you
办法实在是太简单了
have to do is set the new focus
你只需要把新的聚焦行为属性
behavior property to focusable
设置为可聚焦
and that's it, it's that easy.
然后就行了 就这么简单
FocusBehavior is a new property
FocusBehavior 是 SCNNode 上的
on SCNNode and we've also made
一种新属性  我们让 SKNode
this property available on
也支持这一属性
SKNode so now it's even easier
所以现在就可以更轻松地
to make your SpriteKit nodes
让你的 SpriteKit 节点
focusable as well.
同样也可聚焦
But I think it would be a lot
不过我觉得
more fun to just show you this
不如给大家快速演示一遍
in action with a quick demo.
这样会更加有趣
All right, I've been building a
好的 我已经创建了
tic-tac-toe app for tvOS and I
一个基于 tvOS 的三连棋游戏 App
really wanted my app to just
我很想让我的 App
have an extra bit of pop and so
增加一点弹出的特效
I decided to implement it with
所以我决定用 SceneKit
SceneKit.
来执行它
And so, you can see my
现在你可以看见
three-dimensional tic-tac-toe
全方位视角下的
board with full perspective and
立体三连棋盘
I've already implement focus
我已经在我的三连棋游戏里
interaction support in my
执行了焦点
tic-tac-toe game.
交互支持
So, I can move focus around
所以我可以使用任何类型的
using any type of input device
输入设备  把焦点移动到
to each of the tiles on my
棋盘上面的任意方块
board.
位置
And if I press Select I can drop
如果我按下 Select
an X or an O anywhere on the
就可以让 X 或 O 在方块里落子
tile, on any tile.
任一个方块都可以
So, implementing this couldn't
所以说  这样执行起来
have been easier, in addition to
实在是再简单不过了
just setting up my SceneKit
除了要设置我的 SceneKit 场景
scene all I had to do was mark
我需要做的事情只不过是
each of the nodes that represent
使用我先前展示的那一行代码
the tiles on the board as
将每一个代表棋盘方块的
focusable using that one line
节点标记为可聚焦
code I showed earlier.
这就可以了
And then provide custom
接下来  还需要使用
animations using those same
Jon 刚才讲过的那些
animation APIs that Jon was just
相同的动画 API
talking about a moment ago.
来提供自定义动画
And that's really all that we
我们要做的全部事情
had to do.
其实就这么多
Now we can fully interact with
现在我们可以跟我们的 SceneKit
our SceneKit scene.
场景进行全面互动
And the focus engine
聚焦引擎会
automatically takes care of
自动为我们处理好
everything else for us.
剩下的工作
In fact, I added two UIKit
事实上 我添加了两个 UIKit
buttons, UI buttons to the
按钮  UI 按钮是添加在
bottom of our SceneKit scene by
我们这个 SceneKit 场景的底部
just placing them on top of our
只要把这些按钮放在
SK view and the focus engine
SK 视图的上方  聚焦引擎
will automatically handle moving
就会自动处理我们这些
focus between our nodes and
节点和按钮之间的
these buttons.
移动焦点
And it'll do the correct thing
它会妥当地进行处理
no matter whether I'm on the
无论我是在
left or right side of the board
棋盘的左边或右边
hitting the correct button based
根据几何角度上
on what's geometrically closer
离我们节点之间最近距离
to our nodes.
点击正确的按钮
And so, that's just a quick demo
以上这些  就是我对
of SceneKit support for focus
SceneKit 对焦点交互的
interaction.
支持的一个简单演示
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
There are just a few more things
当你在自己的 SceneKit 应用
to keep in mind when
和游戏里面执行
implementing focus interaction
对焦点交互的支持时
support in your SceneKit apps
还有其他几件事情
and games.
需要注意
First, SceneKit obviously
首先 SceneKit 显然是
operates in three-dimensional
在三维空间里运行
space, but focus interaction
但焦点交互却是
operates in two-dimensional
运行在二维空间
space.
里面
So how does this work?
这该怎么办呢？
Well when a user tries to move
那么  当一个用户试图
focus in a certain direction
往某个方向移动焦点时
we're going to look for the next
我们就要搜寻下一个  基于这一区域的
focusable SceneKit node based on
可聚焦的 SceneKit 节点
its area as it's drawn onto the
就在这个节点被拖入到屏幕
screen.
的时候
Second, now that we support
其次 既然我们
focus interaction in SceneKit
在 SceneKit 里支持焦点交互
that means we're now also able
这就意味着我们现在
to support your focusable
也能够支持嵌入到
SpriteKit scenes that are
SceneKit 场景之内的
embedded within SceneKit scenes.
可聚焦的 SpriteKit 场景
And in fact, we automatically
实际上 我们自动支持
support moving focus between
UIKit SpriteKit 和 SceneKit 对象之间
UIKit, SpriteKit and SceneKit
移动焦点
objects with no extra work
从大家的角度来说
required on your part.
也并不需要任何额外的操作
So, you can build your user
所以你可以使用任何工具
interface using whatever tools
来创建自己的用户界面
make the most sense for
把 App 里面的不同区域
different areas of your
发挥最大用场
application and focus
而焦点交互支持
interaction support will just
完全可以
work automatically.
自动运行
And then finally, all the focus
最后  我们在 UIKit 里
APIs that we define in UIKit
使用 UIFocusItem 以及
using the UIFocusItem and
UIFocusEnvironment 协议界定的
UIFocusEnvironment protocols
所有焦点 API
also work for SpriteKit and
它们也都支持 SpriteKit
SceneKit.
和 SceneKit
And so, those custom sound and
所以  像 Jon 先前刚解释的
animation APIs like Jon was
那些自定义音效
explaining earlier, those work
和动画 API  它们同样也
for SceneKit as well and really
支持 SceneKit  而且确实
helped to create a more
有助于创造一种更好的
immersive user experience.
浸润式用户体验
To learn more about working with
要想了解更多有关使用
both SceneKit and SpriteKit we
SceneKit 和 SpriteKit 进行工作的情况
encourage you to check out some
希望大家可以查看一下
of these related sessions that
我们在本周内
we're putting on this week.
将要陆续举办的相关议程
Now for our grand finale today
接下来  是我们今天的压轴戏
I'd like to talk about something
我想谈谈某样东西
that definitely affects all of
它绝对会影响到在座的每个人
us and that's debugging.
那就是调试
I'm happy to say that in tvOS 11
我很高兴地告诉大家 我们将在
we're introducing some great new
tvOS 11 里采用某种全新的
focus debugging tools that we've
聚焦调试工具
built right into UIKit.
我们已经把它加入到 UIKit
And first up is live focus
首先要说的是  焦点实时
update logging.
更新日志
By including the
当你在自己的 Xcode
UIFocusLoggingEnabled option in
方案启动参数里加入
your Xcode schemes launch
UIFocusLoggingEnabled 选项
arguments you can turn on live
你就可以开启
focus update logging.
焦点实时更新日志
Now what's really helpful about
这样做的真正好处
this is that for each
是对于每一个被日志记录的
programmatic focus update that
程序化聚焦更新来说
gets logged we're going to
我们都会加入
include a step-by-step outline
关于首选聚焦环境
of the preferred focus
检索逻辑的
environment's search logic that
详细步骤记录
the focus engine used to
聚焦引擎就是使用这个逻辑
determine the next focus item.
来判断下一个聚焦项
And so, this is incredibly
因此这样做的话  对于诊断那些
helpful for diagnosing issues
焦点未能以编码形式
where focus is not
更新到我们希望的状态这种情况
programmatically updating to the
也有非常大的
item that we would expect it to.
帮助
And because these are logs this
因为这些都是日志
can help you diagnose issues
可以为你诊断一些问题
like focus not updating to the
比如焦点在 App 启动
correct item on app launch and
和切换时未能更新到
during transitions.
正确的项目里
However, this tool does come
然而 对于这个工具
with one warning which is that
有一点需要注意  那就是
please only use this for
请将这一工具仅限于
debugging.
调试之用途
There is a nontrivial
随着你在自己的 App 里
performance cost that comes with
添加日志  会产生
adding logging to your
不小的性能成本
application so you never want
以致于你在推出物流 App 时
this enabled for shipping
根本不想
applications.
启用日志
So that's focus update logging.
以上就是聚焦更新日志
The next tool that we're
我们今天要展示的
unveiling today is
下一个工具是
UIFocusDebugger which is a new
UIFocusDebugger
class that we're exposing in
这是我们基于 tvOS 11 而发布的
tvOS 11.
一个新的类
UIFocusDebugger is a tool for
UIFocusDebugger 这个工具是用来
diagnosing focus related issues
在你的 App 运行时
at runtime in your app and this
诊断与焦点有关的问题的
is really cool.
非常酷
It's structured like a miniature
它的构造就像是一个
command line tool that's built
迷你的命令行工具
right into UIKit available for
它就嵌入在 UIKit 里
you to use.
可供你使用
To take advantage of it all you
要利用这个工具 你只需要
need to do is call any of its
在 App 暂停运行时
methods from LLDB while your app
从 LLDB 里调用它的
is paused.
任何一个功能
Let's take a look at some of its
我们来看看
capabilities.
它能做些什么
The simplest one is that you can
它最简单的一项功能
simply call status to quickly
是你可以调用 status  让它在任何时候
print out the currently focused
都能快速给出当前的
item at any time.
聚焦项
And this is often step one in
这通常是在诊断某些与聚焦相关的问题时
diagnosing some focus related
要做的第一步
issue, especially if you can't
尤其是当你不清楚
see where the currently focused
当前聚焦项在哪里
item is.
的时候
Next, you can use the simulate
其次 你可以使用
focus update request from
environment 功能里的模拟聚焦
environment method to diagnose
更新请求  并以此来诊断
issues related to your app's
与你的 App 首选聚焦逻辑
preferred focus logic.
相关的问题
Calling this method is similar
调用这一功能
to calling the
类似于调用
setNeedsFocusUpdate API and
setNeedsFocusUpdate API
having that focus update execute
并在你刚刚导入的这个环境里
on the environment that you pass
执行这一项
in immediately.
焦聚更新
But what's great about this is
而这一功能的好处
it outputs that same
在于它会生成同样的
step-by-step preferred focus
逐级首选聚焦
environment search logic that we
环境搜索逻辑
also include in the live focus
我们在聚焦实时更新日志里
update logging.
也添加了这个逻辑
But with this simulation method
但是  如果通过这个模拟方法
you can simulate any focus
你就可以在自己的 App 里
update anywhere in your
模拟任何一条
application without having to
聚焦更新  而不必
actually trigger that focus
真的要在你的用户界面里
update manually in your UI.
手动触发聚焦更新
And so, this helps with quickly
这有助于
diagnosing different preferred
在 App 的不同位置
focus environments issues in
快速诊断不同的
different places of your app.
首选聚焦环境问题
Personally, my favorite tool in
就我个人而言  我在
UIFocusDebugger is this next
UIFocusDebugger 里最喜欢的工具
method, check focus ability for
是下一个功能 也就是检查项目的
item.
聚焦能力
And this is used to print out a
使用这个功能  可以得到一份列表
list of potential issues that
罗列出可能导致
may cause an item to not be
项目无法聚焦的
focusable.
潜在问题
We've all had that kind of issue
我们都碰到过类似问题
where there is some item on the
屏幕上出现的某个项
screen that we expect to be
我们希望它可以聚焦
focusable, but for some reason
但是由于某些原因
we just can't focus on it and we
我们又无法对它进行聚焦
don't know why.
而且也不知道原因
And in fact, there are many
事实上  有许多
different reasons why an item
不同的原因都会导致
might not be focusable and they
某一个项目无法聚焦
could be issues not just with
这些问题可能不仅在于
that item itself, but with
这个项本身  而是关系到
ancestors of that item that
这个项目的原始项
affect their children.
这个原始项又影响它的子项
And so, this is where this new
那么  这就是这个全新的
focusability for item method
项目聚焦性能功能的
really shines.
真正亮点
It will automatically detect and
它将会自动为你探测
diagnose all of these potential
并诊断所有这些潜在的
issues for you and print out a
问题  并且给出一份
list of the issues that it
问题列表
detects and this allows you to
这样一来  就可以为你
save a ton of time.
节省大量时间
Obviously, investigating all of
显然 仅凭你自己
these issues on your own would
来调查所有这些问题
just be a huge waste of time.
会带来极大的时间浪费
And then finally, like any good
最后我要说的是 像其他所有
command line tool you can always
出色的命令行工具一样  你随时都能获得
just ask UIFocusDebugger for
UIFocusDebugger 的帮助
help and this is going to print
这个工具也会给出
out a detailed list of
一张详细的指令列表
instructions for each of the
从而罗列出
commands that are available and
每个可用命令的说明
so don't worry about remembering
所以不用担心能否
all of these methods right now
马上记住所有这些方法
because the help command has you
因为帮助命令会解决
covered.
你的问题
But the best way to show you all
不过 向你们展示这个新工具的最好方法
these new tools is with a quick
就是简单的演示
demo.
一遍
All right, so I'm in the process
好的  现在我正在
of building a new tvOS
创建一个新的 tvOS 应用
application, but I've already
但是我已经
run into some pretty serious
遇到一些非常严重的
focus related issues so let's
有关聚焦的问题
see if we can figure out what's
那么 我们来看看自己能否弄明白
going on.
发生了什么
I'm going to build and run our
我正准备创建并运行我们的
application.
这个 App
All right, so this is just a
好了  这就是一个
simple app that showcases some
简单的 App
my favorite movies and the first
展示了我最喜欢的电影
thing you might notice is that
你首先会注意到的可能是
nothing appears focused
屏幕上所有的内容都没有
onscreen.
聚焦
And in fact, if I swipe on the
事实上 如果我是在遥控器屏幕上轻扫
remote or if I try to move focus
或者是尝试用方向键
around the screen using the
在屏幕上四处移动焦点
arrow keys nothing appears
都不会出现任何
focused.
聚焦行为
So, I'm at a loss here, don't
这就让我很不明白了
really know what's going, let's
不知道问题究竟出在哪里 我们来
see if UIFocusDebugger can help.
看看 UIFocusDebugger 能否派上用场
We're going to go back to our
我们要回到这个 App
application, pause it, which
暂停运行
will be LLDB and like I was
这会触发 LLDB
saying earlier, a good thing to
就像我刚才说过的那样
check is the status of the
应该要检查的是
current focus system.
当前聚焦系统的状态
So, I'm going to type in
所以我现在要
UIFocusDebugger status and these
输入 UIFocusDebugger 的状态
calls work with both Objective-C
这些调用要和 Objective-C
and Swift as well.
和 Swift 同时运行
And what status is telling me is
我看到的状态是
that there is an item currently
当前已经有一个聚焦项
focused, it's one of those
它是这些海报单元格里的
poster cells.
一个
But obviously, if we take a look
显然 如果我们查看过后
it doesn't appear focused and so
发现它没有显示聚焦
this points to some kind of
这就说明我们这些单元格的
potential issue with the visual
视觉外观存在着某种
appearance of our cells.
潜在的问题
Let's go to our storyboard to
我们到 Storyboard 上再看看
see if we can figure out what's
能否发现问题
going on.
出在哪里
All right, I've got my
好 现在进入了
storyboard, let's open up our
我的 Storyboard  让我们
collection view and we have a
打开集合视图  可以看到
template for our cell and the
我们这个单元格是有模板的
cell contains an image view.
这个单元格包含了一个图像视图
And what we want is for that
我们想达到的效果
image view when the cell is
是在这个单元格被聚焦时
focused to float up above our
这个图片视图会升浮到
UI.
用户界面上方
And now I'm taking a look at
现在我们来看看这个
this I noticed that we forgot to
我注意到
switch on this adjust on
我们先前忘记开启这个
ancestor focus option and this
调节原始聚焦选项了
is what creates that floating
制造上浮效果的就是它
effect and so that's probably
所以 这很可能就是
our issue.
问题所在
Let's rerun our application and
我们再次运行这个 App
see if that fixes it.
看看问题是否已经解决
Awesome, now we can move between
漂亮 现在我们就可以在这些
these cells, it clearly
单元格之间移动了  它清楚地
indicates which cell is
显示出哪个单元格目前处于
currently focused with that
聚焦状态
floating effect so we're looking
通过这个上浮效果就能看出来
in better shape.
所以现在的视觉效果就变好了
There is another issue with this
不过还有另外一个问题
allocation though, which is that
跟这种配置有关  那就是
I can't seem to focus on this
我无法聚焦到
more info button that's in this
App 底部的这个
bottom shelf of our app and I
More Info 按钮
don't really know what's going
我真不知道问题出在哪里
on there, there's nothing I can
我在这里找不到任何
do from here.
解决办法
So, let's go back into our
所以  我们再次回到 App
application and see if we can
看看能不能
figure out what's going on.
找到问题所在
We're going to go to our
我们现在要打开
mainViewController, set up
mainViewController
breakpoints, let's trigger that
设置断点  然后再触发
breakpoints.
那个断点
All right, so this is a great
好  现在是个好机会
opportunity to use that new
我们来试试这个新的
check focus ability method.
检查聚焦能力的方法
I'm going to type in P-O
我现在要输入
UIFocusDebugger.
P-O UIFocusDebugger
What's great is that we get full
很好  我们可以全面获得
autocomplete support and we're
自动填充支持
allowed to invoke this, we need
我们可以调用这个  然后还需要
a Swift code.
一个 Swift 代码
Let's check the focusability of
我们来检查一下
our more info button which I
More Info 按钮的聚焦能力
have an outlet referenced to.
这个按钮我已经让它关联了一个输出口
All right, so it detected an
好的 它检测到一个问题
issue and what this is telling
它现在告诉我们
us is that the item is being
这个项的当前状况是
visually occluded, that's
视觉上被遮挡住了
visually blocked by some other
也就是说 它被屏幕上的
item on the screen.
另外某个项遮蔽住了
And it really helpfully even
它甚至还为我们
printed out a reference to the
找出某个项的引用参考
item that it thinks is causing
它认为这个项是导致问题的
the problem.
原因所在
Let's go back to our storyboard
我们再回到 Storyboard 上
to see if we can figure out
看看我们能否找到
what's going on here.
问题出在哪里
All right, I'm going to go to
好的  我现在准备打开
our mainViewController.
mainViewController
All right, so here's our more
好  我们的 More Info 按钮
info button.
就在这里
So, it said that we were being
那么  它说我们被
visually occluded by some other
某个项进行了视觉遮挡
item, but I can obviously see
但是我明显可以看到
this more info button here so
这个 More Info 按钮就在这里
what's going on.
那么这到底是怎么回事
Well now I'm looking at the
我现在看一下 Storyboard
storyboard I notice this other
我注意到我们这个
sibling view to our more info
More Info 按钮的
button and this is a
兄弟视图
semitransparent white view that
这是一个半透明的白色视图
we use as the background of the
我们用它来做
bottom shelf in our application.
这个 App 底部展架的背景
And I'm noticing that this view
我注意到这个视图
was accidentally placed on top
被误放在我们这个
of our more info button, but
More Info 按钮的上方
that was really hard to see
但是这确实很难看出来
because it's semitransparent.
因为它是半透明的
So, let's try dragging this just
所以我们试试把这个视图
below our more info button and
拖到 More Info 按钮的下面
relaunch our application and see
然后重启这个 App
if that fixes the issue.
看看问题有没有解决
All right, let's try that again.
好  我们再试一次
All right, make that a little
把它稍微再放大
bit bigger.
一点点
Okay now I can go and focus on
OK 现在我可以聚焦到
that more info button.
这个 More Info 按钮上了
As our application is looking in
我们这个 App 的图形效果
better shape now we can start to
变好了  现在我们可以
move on to the more important
转到更重要的
work of building out our new
事情上面  那就是创建我们的
features.
新功能
Let's [inaudible] back to the
我们现在回到这个
presentation.
展示画面
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
So that's just a quick example
刚刚只是简单示范了一下
of how UIFocusDebugger helped us
UIFocusDebugger 是如何帮助我们
to identify those kinds of
识别这类简单
simple mistakes that are easy to
而且可以轻松解决的错误
fix, but that can nonetheless
但这样多少也会
waste a ton of time during
在 App 的开发过程中
application development as we
浪费我们许多时间
try to track them down.
因为我们要把这些问题追踪到底
So that's focused debugging in
这就是基于 tvOS 11 的
tvOS 11.
聚焦调试
To recap our session for today.
简单概括一下我们今天的会议
Please take advantage of the new
请好好利用这些
focus update notifications and
全新的聚焦更新通知和
the protocol extension methods
协议扩展功能
that we're adding in tvOS 11 in
我们把它们添加到 tvOS 11  是为了
order to accomplish common tasks
用更少的代码去完成
with less code.
常规任务
You can use the new animation
你可以使用新的动画 API 和
APIs and the custom sound APIs
自定义音效 API
that Jon was talking about
Jon 刚在本次议程里
earlier in this session in order
谈到过它们
to provide a more immersive
它们可以为你的 App 和游戏提供
experience for your apps and
更好的浸润式
games.
体验
Definitely check out the new
大家一定要试试
focus interaction support in
SceneKit 里全新的
SceneKit.
焦点交互支持
This is a great way to add
这是一个非常棒的工具
interactivity to your SceneKit
可以为你的 SceneKit 游戏增加
games.
交互性
And then finally, use the new
最后  使用全新的
focus debugging tools to save
聚焦调试工具  可以给自己
yourself a lot of time.
节省大量的时间
For more information on today's
关于今天会议的更多信息
session, you can go to
大家可以登录
developer.apple.com.
developer.apple.com 查看
If you're interested in learning
如果你有兴趣
more about developing for tvOS
深入学习 tvOS 开发
you can check out some of these
可以查看我们在本周
related sessions that we're
将陆续推出的
putting on this week.
相关会议
Thank you very much.
非常感谢